Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection1918-1996 (bulk 1940-1959)
ML31.H69
Lester Horton Dance Theater
11,508 items 71 containers 22 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lester Horton was a choreographer, dancer, and teacher. The collection, which documents Horton's personal and professional life and the activities of the Lester Horton Dance Theater, contains correspondence, writings, music, publicity and production materials, programs, teaching materials, business papers, scrapbooks, news clippings, publications, costume and set designs, photographs, and drawings.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Ailey, Alvin.; Bowne, William.; Cunningham, Merce.; De Lavallade, Carmen, 1931-; Eng, Frank--Correspondence.; Eng, Frank.; Eng, Frank.; Goldoni, Lelia.; Hamilton, Judith, composer.; Horton, Lester, 1906-1953--Correspondence.; Horton, Lester, 1906-1953--Photographs.; Horton, Lester, 1906-1953.; Horton, Lester, 1906-1953.; Horton, Lester, 1906-1953. Lester Horton Dance Theater collection. 1918-1996.; Itō, Michio, 1893-1961.; Lewitzky, Bella.; Lloyd, Margaret.; Martin, Don, 1931-; Paz, Juan Carlos, 1897-1972.; Trisler, Joyce, 1934-1979.; Truitte, James.; Warren, Larry--Correspondence.; Warren, Larry.
Organizations
Horton (Lester) Collection (Library of Congress); Lester Horton Dance Theater--Archives.; Lester Horton Dance Theater.; Lester Horton Dance Theater.
Subjects
Choreographers--United States.; Choreography--United States.; Costume design--United States.; Dance companies--United States.; Dance schools--United States.; Dance teachers--United States.; Dance--Production and direction.; Dance--Stage-setting and scenery--United States.; Dance--Study and teaching.; Dance--United States.; Dancers--Photographs.; Modern dance--United States.; Music--Manuscripts.
Form/Genre
Artifacts (Object genre); Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Photographic prints.; Programs (Documents); Promotional materials.; Scrapbooks.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Purchase; Frank Eng, former business manager of Dance Theater and Horton's heir; 1995.
Acquisition; Larry Warren, Horton biographer; 1996.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Transfers
Audiovisual materials have been transferred to the Library of Congress, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division.
Access and Restrictions
The Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Sketch
Dancer-teacher-choreographer Lester Horton (1906-1953) is regarded as one of the founders of American modern dance. He developed a unique style of technique and choreography, established the first permanent theater in America devoted to dance, and organized one of the first integrated modern dance companies.
Born and raised in Indiana, Horton's early interests in art, ballet, theater production, and Native American dance led him to participate in local dance pageants. Settling in Los Angeles in the late 1920s, Horton danced with Michio Ito's company and then formed his own group. His company gave concert performances at major Los Angeles venues such as the Hollywood Bowl and the Greek Theater while Horton continued to teach young dancers. A Los Angeles base and the ability to translate ethnic dances into commercially acceptable formats led to stints choreographing musical numbers for films from the 1940s through the early 1950s.
Throughout his career, Horton combined dance and drama into a total theatrical experience. He was intimately involved in creating all aspects of a production: the costumes, sets, lighting, and music as well as the scenarios and choreography. His fascination with ethnic dance, human sensuality, and cultural history was expressed in a prodigious body of work with themes ranging from the classics to melodrama, social concerns to farce. Horton's "choreodramas" were built on a movement technique that is still taught and used in dance schools and companies.
Horton's company members and students included well-known modern dancers such as Alvin Ailey, Janet Collins, Carmen de Lavallade, Bella Lewitzky, James Mitchell, Joyce Trisler, and James Truitte. Horton collaborated with Lewitzky to develop the foundation of his technique; they joined forces with several other partners to found the Dance Theater in Hollywood in 1946. Dance Theater was the home of the dance company and the school, which featured dance classes for children and adults. The full curriculum developed well-rounded dancers who were also taught art history and theater production. After the partnership dissolved in 1950, Horton maintained Dance Theater with the assistance of business manager Frank Eng, mounting several successful seasons until his death in 1953. Eng sustained the theater for seven more years before closing its doors in 1960.
Scope and Content Note
The Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection is a collection of multi-format materials documenting the work of dancer-teacher-choreographer Lester Horton as well as the workings of a modern dance company in California. The collection consists of correspondence, writings, publicity and production materials, programs, costume and set designs, news clippings, teaching materials, music, photographs, business papers, scrapbooks, drawings, publications, and audiovisual materials (the audiovisual materials were transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division of the Library of Congress). The collection spans the years 1926 to 1996, with the bulk of the materials dated from the 1940s through the 1950s. Since Horton's private life was intertwined with his professional one, the collection includes information on both. Individuals represented include Alvin Ailey, William Bowne, Merce Cunningham, Carmen De Lavallade, Frank Eng, Lelia Goldoni, Judith Hamilton, Michio Itō, Bella Lewitzky, Margaret Lloyd, Don Martin, Joyce Trisler, James Truitte, and Larry Warren.
The collection provides a record of Horton's creative output as a modern dance pioneer and of the workings of an early, struggling modern dance company and school. The materials in the collection document his creative process in areas such as dance technique, dance training, and performance production. It also provides evidence of the day-to-day administration of the theater, school, and company, as well as Horton's personal and professional relationships.
Many items in the collection were not labeled or dated at the time of their creation. Other items were lost over time or are otherwise not part of this collection. Horton's creative process also affected the documentation and resulting record in the collection. He often reworked a dance piece, altering aspects such as the costuming, music, and choreography. For some programs he created "suites" that included a number of individual dances. At times he would use the "same" piece (title) in different suites; at other times he worked on a piece intended for a suite that did not appear in the final, performed version.
Therefore, every effort has been made to link individual items with the appropriate dance work and/or suite, in all pertinent series and sub-series such as costume and set designs, photographs, and music. Knowledge of his repertory and style and other research led to many of the identifications listed. Cases where identifications were uncertain are indicated with a question mark. All performance works are listed with the suite title first.
The audiovisual materials in the collection include record albums, instantaneous disks, open reel tapes, audio cassette tapes, videocassettes, and film. The sound recordings consist of music used in classes, rehearsals, and performance as well as interviews by biographer Larry Warren. The moving image materials include copies of television shows featuring Horton works and an interview with Frank Eng. All audiovisual materials are located in the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division (MBRS) of the Library of Congress and are subject to that Division's policies for use and reproduction. These items are listed in the Sound Recordings appendix. They are arranged by format and listed alphabetically by title. The catalogue or record number is included if that information is available.
Michelle Forner, April 1997
Organization of the Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection
The Lester Horton Dance Theater Collection is organized in twelve series:
Writings, 1929-1992
Correspondence, 1939-1996
Production Materials
Teaching Materials
Publicity, 1926-1996
Programs, 1927-1996
Music, 1918-1958
Photographic Materials, 1930-1965
Drawings
Scrapbooks, 1929-1950
Business Papers, 1930-1975
Publications
http://lccn.loc.gov/2003682045
Container List
- Writings, 1929-1992 (Box 1-2)
  The writings are arranged in the following subseries: By Lester Horton, About Lester Horton, and By Frank Eng. The materials span the years 1929 to 1992. Horton's writings include published and unpublished material on his work and ethnic dance, including a manuscript on Salome, his seminal choreodrama that he reworked throughout his career. Also included are autograph notebooks and papers that record bits and pieces of his creative process. Writings about Horton include published articles and a copy of Larry Warren's biography, as well as a typewritten transcript of a recording of Bella Lewitzky regarding Horton. Writings by Frank Eng include drafts of articles, several unpublished manuscripts, and autograph and typewritten notes and notebooks. A writer by trade, Eng's many articles and memoirs reflect his perspective as an intimate of Horton and the business manager of Dance Theater.
  Arranged by subseries and then chronologically.
  - By Lester Horton (Box-folder 1/1-8)
    - The Indian in his native art (Box-folder 1/1)
    - On Salome, The face of violence (Box-folder 1/2)
    - [Published articles] 1929-47 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - [Notes] (Box-folder 1/4)
    - [Notebook] (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Personal notes [notebook] (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Personal [notebook] (Box-folder 1/7)
    - [Notebook] (Box-folder 1/8)
  - About Lester Horton (Box-folder 1/9-11)
    - Lester Horton: Modern dance pioneer by Larry Warren, 1977 [book] (Box-folder 1/9)
    - [Published articles] 1937, 1948, 1954-78, 1992 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - [Unpublished interview with Bella Lewitzky] 1967 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - By Frank Eng (Box 2)
    - [Drafts] (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Early research, Dance Perspectives article (Box-folder 2/2)
    - [Manuscripts] (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Lester Horton, American dance pioneer (Horton triad), 1966 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Memoirs of a man of displeasure (Horton triad), 1948 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Rivers and streams, part I (Horton triad), 1974 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Rivers and streams, part II (Horton triad), 1980 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Material from [la?] notebook, 1957-59 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - [Notebook, large] (Box-folder 2/9)
    - [Notebook, large-loose sheets] (Box-folder 2/10)
    - [Notebook, small] (Box-folder 2/11)
    - [Notes] (Box-folder 2/12)
- Correspondence, 1939-1996 (Box 3-6)
  The correspondence consists of autograph and typewritten drafts, originals, and carbon copies about professional as well as personal matters. It spans the years 1939 to 1996, with the bulk of the material dated between the late 1940s and the late 1950s. The letters are arranged alphabetically by letterhead or name of the correspondent who was writing to either Frank Eng (the majority), Lester Horton, or Larry Warren. The series also includes letters from these individuals, filed alphabetically under the correspondent's name or letterhead.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - 5 by 2 Dance Company, 1975 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Abner J. Greshler Agency, 1955-57 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Ailey, Alvin, 1955-76 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Allied Arts Corporation, 1952 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - American Guild of Musical Artists, Inc., 1951 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - American Guild of Variety Artists, 1954-59 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Ames, Ransey, 1949 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Anawalt, Sasha,1985-86 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Arlen, Walter, 1964 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - "A" miscellaneous, 1950-56 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Bauer, John, 1951 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Bennett & Pleasant, 1953-54 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Bowne, William, 1951-66 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences, 1949-68 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - "B" miscellaneous, 1950-73 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - California, Department of Education, 1946-54 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - California, Franchise Tax Board, 1958-62 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Chávez, Carlos, n.d. (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Chester, Anne, 1954 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Cincinnati Ballet Company, 1971-73 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Cocoanut Grove, 1959 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Community Concerts, 1952-58 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Cunningham, Merce, 1951 (Box-folder 3/23)
  - "C" miscellaneous, 1941-67 (Box-folder 3/24)
  - Dance Magazine, 1947-53 (Box-folder 3/25)
  - Dance News, 1949-53 (Box-folder 3/26)
  - Dance Notation Bureau Inc., 1971-84 (Box-folder 3/27)
  - Dance Observer, 1949-53 (Box-folder 3/28)
  - Dance Perspectives, 1966-68 (Box-folder 3/29)
  - Dance Theater, 1949-76 (Box-folder 3/30)
  - Dance Theater of Harlem, Inc., 1971-96 (Box-folder 3/31)
  - De Lavallade, Carmen, 1953-58 (Box-folder 3/32)
  - De Lavallade, Yvonne, n.d. (Box-folder 3/33)
  - Detroit Public Library, 1954-55 (Box-folder 3/34)
  - "D" miscellaneous, 1950-76 (Box-folder 3/35)
  - "E" miscellaneous, 1941-69 (Box-folder 3/36)
  - First Unitarian Church, 1954 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Ford Foundation, 1956, n.d. (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Franks, Michael, n.d. (Box-folder 4/3)
  - "F" miscellaneous, 1940-55 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Golberg, Albert, 1953-60 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Goldoni, Lelia, 1959-93 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Grosset and Dunlap, Inc., 1972 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - "G" miscellaneous, 1946-61 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Haggart, Stanley, 1953-56 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Hamilton, Judith, 1949-79 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Hill, Jack, 1961-85 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Harrison, Lou, 1968 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Hollywood Bowl Association, 1937 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Horton Dance Group, 1939 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Horton, Lester (references), 1947 (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Horton Reconstruction Committee, 1974 (Box-folder 4/16)
  - "H" miscellaneous, 1949-77 (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Inner City Cultural Center, 1970-77 (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Ito, Michio, 1955 (Box-folder 4/19)
  - "I" miscellaneous, 1944-55 (Box-folder 4/20)
  - Jacob's Pillow Dance Festival, Inc., 1953-54 (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Joyce Trisler Danscompany, 1966 (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Juilliard School, Dance Division, 1952 (Box-folder 4/23)
  - "J" miscellaneous, 1929-55 (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Kawasumi, Misaye, 1983 (Box-folder 4/25)
  - Kerr, Joan, 1972 (Box-folder 4/26)
  - King, William E. see: San Diego Symphony
  - "K" miscellaneous, 1938-76 (Box-folder 4/27)
  - League of Allied Arts, 1958-59 (Box-folder 4/28)
  - Lewitzky, Bella, 1949-75 (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Little Theatre of the Verdugos, 1933 (Box-folder 4/30)
  - Lloyd, Margaret, 1947-54 (Box-folder 4/31)
  - Los Angeles Herald Express, 1950-85 (Box-folder 4/32)
  - Los Angeles Times, 1949-85 (Box-folder 4/33)
  - Love, Frank H., 1951-60 (Box-folder 4/34)
  - "L" miscellaneous, 1940-85 (Box-folder 4/35)
  - Maracci, Carmelita, 1953 (Box-folder 4/36)
  - Martin, Donald, 1950-83 (Box-folder 4/37)
  - Martin, John, 1968 (Box-folder 4/38)
  - Martinez, Elsie, 1933-40, 1967 (Box-folder 4/39)
  - Metro Goldwyn Mayer Pictures, 1957 (Box-folder 4/40)
  - Mosk, Edward, 1955-73 (Box-folder 4/41)
  - "M" miscellaneous, 1944-72 (Box-folder 4/42)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, Dance Division, 1968-73 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - New York Public Library, 1961-74 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - New York Times, 1949-72 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - "N" miscellaneous, 1934-58 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Occidental College, 1946-50 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Ojai Festivals Ltd., 1951 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - "O" miscellaneous, 1949-64 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Paul, Stanley, 1950-54 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Paul Stefen Dancers, 1953 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Paz, Juan Carlos, 1940 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Pierce, Luisa, 1968 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - de Prida, Pablo, 1940-41 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Pryor-Menz Concert Service, 1949-52 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - "P" miscellaneous, 1940-85 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - "Q" miscellaneous, 1952-56 (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Ramona High School, 1958 (Box-folder 5/16)
  - "R" miscellaneous, 1946-65 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - San Diego Symphony, 1954 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - San Francisco Ballet, 1973 (Box-folder 5/19)
  - San Francisco Contemporary Dancers, 1958 (Box-folder 5/20)
  - Satoru Shimazaki & Dancers, 1982 (Box-folder 5/21)
  - Shagan, Rena, 1975 (Box-folder 5/22)
  - Smuin, Michael, 1973 (Box-folder 5/23)
  - Solomon, Vida, 1953-54 (Box-folder 5/24)
  - State University of Iowa, 1954 (Box-folder 5/25)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1939 (Box-folder 5/26)
  - "S" miscellaneous, 1936-94 (Box-folder 5/27)
  - Time Magazine, 1973 (Box-folder 5/28)
  - Truitte, James, 1956-76 (Box-folder 5/29)
  - "T" miscellaneous, 1951-75 (Box-folder 5/30)
  - Union Institute, 1995-96 (Box-folder 5/31)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1938-75 (Box-folder 5/32)
  - University of Chicago, 1949-60 (Box-folder 5/33)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1971-73 (Box-folder 5/34)
  - University of Southern California, 1957-69 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - "U" miscellaneous, 1949-74 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Unidentified, 1945-86, n.d. (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Veterans Administration, 1950-53 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Villa-Lobos, Heitor, 1940 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - "V" miscellaneous, 1949-76 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Warren, Larry, 1953-77 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - WCBS-TV, 1963 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - William Morris Agency, 1951 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - "W" miscellaneous, 1949-75 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Young, Marl, 1959 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Young Men's & Young Women's Hebrew Association, 1937-53 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Yuma Community Concert Association, 1952-53 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - "Z" miscellaneous, 1949-55 (Box-folder 6/14)
- Production Materials (Box 7, Box 8, Box-folder 43/1)
  The production materials consist of manuscripts, graphic materials, and realia related to the performance of Horton works. The series is arranged by subject in the following order: Scenarios and Related Materials, Repertoire and Castings, Plays, Notes/Miscellaneous, Costume Designs, Set Designs, Set Piece, and Props. The scenarios, which are arranged alphabetically by title, include typewritten and holograph descriptions, outlines, drafts, and notes concerning Horton choreographic works, including some that were never performed. Of note is a rhythm score for Salome with choreographic notes, Labanotation of The Beloved, and a light plot for Liberian Suite. The three plays in the series, all by Horton colleague Sonia Brown, include scripts that may or may not have been used by Horton for choreographic works.
  The costume and set designs in the Collection, created mostly by Horton and Bill Bowne, are among the few surviving examples of production design for early American modern dance. The drawings, sketches, and paintings were made with pen, pencil, or mixed media, predominantly on tracing and construction paper. They are arranged alphabetically by title of work, which may or may not have been performed. Although many of the designs are not labeled with dates or titles, they are recognizable as belonging to a certain work or suite. The date span of the materials is approximately 1932 to 1952. The several props in the series, such as the bible used in The Beloved and the drum from Totem Incantation, are arranged alphabetically by title of work.
  Arranged by subject.
  - Scenarios & related materials (Box 7, Box-folder 43/1)
    - Annie get your gun (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Barrel house (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Barrel house (Box-folder 43/1)
    - The beloved (Box-folder 7/3-4)
    - Brown county, Indiana (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Carnival in (Bahia, Recife or ?) (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Carolina and the Quaker (Box-folder 7/7)
    - The curious will of Josiah Manners (Box-folder 7/8)
    - The cottonwood leaves are whisperin' (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Dancing Americans (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Dybbuk (Box-folder 7/11)
    - The family (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Girl crazy (Box-folder 7/13)
    - House in the country (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Liberian suite (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Medicine show (Box-folder 7/16)
    - De morte (Box-folder 7/17)
    - The park (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Phoenix aground (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Prado de pena (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Recuerdo de angustia (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Rites of spring [Le sacre du printemps] (Box-folder 7/22)
    - Salome (Box-folder 7/23)
    - Salty dog (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Sixteen to twenty-four (Box-folder 7/25)
    - Sleeping beauty (Box-folder 7/26)
    - Something to please everybody (Box-folder 7/27)
    - Song of Hiawatha (Box-folder 7/28)
    - St. Francis (Box-folder 7/29)
    - Tierra y libertad! (Box-folder 7/30)
    - Tongue and cheek (Box-folder 7/31)
    - Warsaw ghetto (Box-folder 7/32)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 7/33)
    - White savage (Box-folder 7/34)
  - Repertoire and castings (Box 8)
    - Items (Box-folder 8/1)
- Teaching Materials (Box 9)
  The teaching materials in the Collection consist of typewritten and handwritten manuscripts that describe the courses, classes, and dance technique offered primarily through Dance Theater. They are arranged by subject in the following order: Course Descriptions/Outlines, Lecture Demonstrations, Technique Descriptions, Lesson Plans and Course Outlines, and Labanotation of Technique. The course descriptions, developed by Horton and others, summarize the goals, objectives, and material covered in classes on dance technique (multiple levels), art history, theater practice, and so forth. The materials on lecture demonstrations such as "Introduction to the Dance" include Horton's notes and outlines of the programs he presented to educate the public on dance and his technique. The teaching materials also include lesson plans, course outlines, and technique descriptions (including Labanotation) by Carmen de Lavallade and other Horton disciples.
  - Course descriptions/outlines (Box-folder 9/1-15)
    - Adult workshop (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Advanced professional technique (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Advanced technique (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Art history II (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Choreography (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Choreography workshop (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Composition (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Dance research (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Design for dance production II/Theater design II (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Elementary progression (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Fundamentals technique (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Intermediate technique (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Movement for actors (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Theatrical practise (Box-folder 9/15)
  - Lecture demonstrations (Box-folder 9/16-17)
    - Introduction to the dance (Box-folder 9/16)
    - Children's lecture-demonstration (Box-folder 9/17)
  - Technique descriptions (Box-folder 9/18)
    - By others (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Lesson plans and course outlines (Box-folder 9/19)
    - By others (Box-folder 9/19)
  - Labanotation of technique (Box-folder 9/20)
    - Items (Box-folder 9/20)